Guide to the George Breitman Papers TAM.169
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III. Political Organizations and Activities, 1930-1986; 34 Linear Feet in 34 containers
  - Subseries B: Other Organizations, 1934-1986
    - Evans on the History of the International, March 30, 1973; cuid42892 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0142)
      Preservation Note: The tape was reshelled; the audio quality is very poor, with the audio being muffled/muted and difficult to decipher.
    - "The Liberating Influence of the Transitional Program: The Ludlow Amendment" by George Breitman, August, 1974; cuid42841 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0053)
    - "The Liberating Influence of the Transitional Program: The Labor Party Question" by George Breitman, August, 1974; cuid42842 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0054)
    - "The Liberating Influence of the Transitional Program: The Socialist Workers Party, Then and Now" by George Breitman, August, 1974; cuid42843 (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0055)
    - Fourth International, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Fourth International, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Fourth International, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Fourth International, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency Discussion, April 28, 1984; cuid42905
      Includes discussion with Frank Lovell
      - Part one, cuid42905A (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0164)
      - Part two, cuid42905B (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0165)
      - Part three, cuid42905C (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0166)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency Discussion, October 13, 1984; cuid42906 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0167)
    - Fourth International, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency Conference, New York, 1985; cuid42907
      - Part one, cuid42907A (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0168)
      - Part two, cuid42907B (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0169)
      - Part three, cuid42907C (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0170)
    - Steve Bloom -- "The Fourth International Today" Forum, August 20, 1987; cuid42898 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0149)
      Preservation Note: Reception interference is heard throughout.
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency Conference, New York, January 11, 1987; cuid42908 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0171)
      Preservation Note: Side 1 has poor audio quality.
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency Conference, 1989; cuid42909 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0172)
      Includes Pre-Conf Discussion and "T+P Tom"
    - Fourth International, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Jan 1984-Feb 1984 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Mar 1984 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Apr 1984 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, May 1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Jun 1984 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Jul 1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Aug 1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Sep 1984 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Oct 1984 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Nov 1984 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Dec 1984 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Handbook for Marxist Studies, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Minutes, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Minutes - Cleveland Organizing Committee, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Minutes - Los Angeles, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Minutes - Philadelphia Organizing Committee, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Jan 1985-Feb 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Mar 1985-Apr 1985 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, May 1985-Jun 1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Jul 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Sep 1985-Oct 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, Nov 1985-Dec 1985 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents - Bulletin in Defense of Marxism #16, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents - Bulletin in Defense of Marxism #17, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents - Bulletin in Defense of Marxism #18, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents - Weissman, George - Memorial, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Minutes, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Fourth Internationalist Tendency: Correspondence/Documents, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Tom Kerry on the History of the Fourth Internationalist Tendency, Undated; cuid42877
      - Part one, cuid42877A (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0122)
        Preservation Note: The overall audio quality varies, and side 2 has poorer audio quality than side 1.
      - Part two, cuid42877B (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0123)
        Preservation Note: The overall audio quality varies.
      - Part three, cuid42877C (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0124)
    - Trotsky and Novak on the Founding of the Fourth International, Undated; cuid42855 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0075)
      Preservation Note: The audio quality is poor overall, but the first 11:21 is very difficult to decipher.
    - "The Industrial Workers of the World" by James P. Cannon, Undated; cuid42852
      - Part one, cuid42852A (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0069)
      - Part two, cuid42852B (Box 70, Audiocassette 169_0070)
        Preservation Note: The first 43 seconds of side 1 are very muted and have poor audio quality. The first 30 seconds of side 2 are very muted and have poor audio quality.
    - League for a Revolutionary Workers Party, 1935 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Action, Jan 1983-Oct 1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Action, Nov 1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Action, Dec 1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Socialist Action, Jan 1984 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Socialist Action, Feb 1984-May 1984 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Action, Jun 1984 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Socialist Action, 1985-1986 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Socialist Action, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Party - Hansen, Joe - letters to Max Shachtman, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Party - internal documents, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Party - Muste, A.J. "War is the central problem today..." [14 pages, untitled typescript], 1936 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Socialist Party - National Action Committee minutes, 1937 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Socialist Party - National Action Committee minutes (1937), Breitman notes thereon, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Party - Newark, NJ, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Spartacus Youth League, 1934-1936 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Workers Alliance, 1930s (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Workers Party US, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Workers Party US, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Workers Party US National Committee, Oct 1935 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Workers Party US, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Workers Party US National Committee: Oct-1936 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Workers Party US "What next in the Scottsboro case?" ("They shall not die" is not enough), 1936 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Workers Party US, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - World Congress Report, Undated; cuid43034 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0128)
      Preservation Note: The sound is muddy.
- Series IV. Writings, Lectures, and Interviews, 1919-1989; 4.5 Linear Feet in 26 containers
  Series IV. Writings, Lectures, and Interviews contains correspondence, published and unpublished typescripts, transcripts of speeches and lectures, lists of articles in Trotskyist periodicals, and audio recordings of lectures, interviews, and events.
  Subseries B and C contain typescripts relating to Malcolm X and the Black Power and Civil Rights movements, including that of a proposed book, Racism in World War II, and The SWP and the Negro Question; a 1939 typescript by J. R. Johnson (aka C. L. R. James) "Preliminary notes on the Negro Question;" ephemera documenting the Black Liberation movements of the late 1950s - early 1970s, notably the Freedom Now Party; transcripts of speeches, interviews, lectures, and radio broadcasts by Malcolm X; correspondence, including Eldridge Cleaver (see also series I) and James Shabazz; and lists of relevant articles in Trotskyist periodicals.
  The series also contains Cannon correspondence, writings and interviews, and Breitman's correspondence regarding the editing and publication of Cannon's writings. It contains a selection of Trotsky's correspondence and writings, as well as several letters from U.S. Trotskyists and Breitman's correspondence regarding his editing and publication of the works of Trotsky.
  Breitman corresponded with Carl Skoglund, Minneapolis Trotskyist and Teamster leader, regarding what appears to have been a biography, and the files contain fragmentary portions of the unpublished typescript. Breitman also corresponded with historian Alan Wald, with Trotsky bibliographer Louis Sinclair and others, including Pierre Broue, Trotsky's grandson (four files covering the years 1972-1983). Breitman also accumulated a number of typescripts by other Trotskyists.
  This series is arranged into eleven subseries:
  Subseries A: Writings, General
  Subseries B: Party History
  Subseries C: Malcolm X
  Subseries D: African-Americans
  Subseries E: James P. Cannon
  Subseries F: Leon Trotsky
  Subseries G: Carl Skoglund
  Subseries H: Alan Wald correspondence
  Subseries I: Louis Sinclair Correspondence
  Subseries J: General Correspondence
  Subseries K: Writings by Others
  - Subseries A: Writings, general, 1953-1978
    - Soviet Union and Stalinism [talk, notes], circa 1953 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Lesser evil politics, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Castroism - revolutionary or centrist?; other Cuba writings, circa 1978 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - George Breitman interviewed by Jon Bloom, January 4, 1979; cuid42903
      - Part one, cuid42903A (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0158)
        Breitman discusses his youth, the beginnings of his interest in radical politics, and the Unemployed Workers Movement during the 1930s.
        Preservation Note: Side 1 has inconsitent audio quality and crackling is heard throughout. Side 2 also has crackling throughout.
      - Part two, cuid42903B (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0159)
        Preservation Note: The microphone on side 1 was too hot, so there is distortion and the audio is too loud.
        Breitman discusses the Unemployment Movement, the Socialist Workers Party (SWP), running for political office, and serving in the Second World War.
      - Part three, cuid42903C (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0160)
        Breitman discusses serving in the Second World War, his activities after the war, the American Radical Movement, and the James Kutcher case.
    - George Breitman - Jon Bloom, January 4, 1979; cuid42904
      - Part one, cuid42904A (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0161)
        Preservation Note: The tape had to be incubated for successful digitization.
      - Part two, cuid42904B (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0162)
        Preservation Note: A significant print-through echo can be heard and while it's distracting, it doesn't impact comprehension.
      - Part two, cuid42904C (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0163)
    - George Breitman on the Left Opposition in the US, January, 1984; cuid42899 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0150)
      An educational presentation at the New York branch of Socialist Action
    - Jean Jaurès portrait--postcard, 1985 (Box Shared Tamiment 165, Folder 15)
    - George Breitman on Robert Allen's Book, Undated; cuid42881 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0131)
    - Breitman on the Bill of Rights [talk], undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Breitman on Fiction, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Lenin reading notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Lists of Breitman Writings, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Prospects for socialism in the U.S. [talk], undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - State capitalism, Bonapartism [lecture notes], undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Workers and farmers government/question, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - World War II era, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Postcards -- socialist-realist murals, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 165, Folder 15)
  - Subseries B: Socialist Workers Party History, 1970s-1981
    - Socialist Workers Party Political Comm Meeting, January, 1969; cuid42894 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0144)
      Discussion of New York City Mayoral campaign and the transitional program
    - George Breitman on the New Radicalization, August, 1970; cuid42900 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0152)
      The new radicalization compared with those of the past by George Breitman in Oberlin, Ohio
      Preservation Note: The audio is muffled.
    - "The New Radicalization and the Revolutionary Party" by Jack Barnes, Oberlin, 1970; cuid42886 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0136)
      Preservation Note: The audio is muffled and there is periodic interference with the microphone.
    - "Our Opponents and the New Radicalization" by Peter Camejo, Oberlin, 1970; cuid42889 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0139)
      Preservation Note: The audio is muffled and the overall quality is poor.
    - Socialist Workers Party Organizational Norms by Evelyn Sells, December 11, 1976; cuid42896 (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0146)
      Preservation Note: Some audio distortion can be heard on side 1. Some audio distortion and channel shifting can be heard on side 2.
    - Party History: Correspondence re compilation of lists of names, chronologies, etc, 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Party History: The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party - correspondence and notes, 1980-1981 (Box 43A, Folder 1)
    - Degeneration of the Socialist Workers Party, March 8, 1987; cuid42893 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0143)
    - George Breitman on Socialist Workers Party History, Undated; cuid42876
      - Part one, cuid42876B (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0121)
      - Part two, cuid42876A (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0120)
    - Organizational Norms of the Socialist Workers Party by Beatrice Hansen, Undated; cuid42884 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0134)
    - Organizational Principles of the Socialist Workers Party by Beatrice Hansen with a tribute to Beatrice Hansen, Undated; cuid42883 (Box 71, Audiocassette 169_0133)
    - Party History: "The Expelled", undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Party History: The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party - glossary, undated (Box 43A, Folder 2)
    - Party History: The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party - part 6 (2nd convention), undated (Box 43A, Folder 3)
    - Party History: The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party - preface, undated (Box 43A, Folder 4)
    - Party History: The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party - indexes, lists, other reference tools, undated (Box 43A, Folder 5)
    - Party History: "Report to the Political Committee on the character of the present period" (Breitman), circa 1970s (Box 43A, Folder 6)
    - PC 32, Undated; cuid42902
      PC may stand for Party Conference.
      - Part one, cuid42902A (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0154)
        Preservation Note: The volume is low.
      - Part two, cuid42902B (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0155)
      - Part three, cuid42902C (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0156)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality is poor and crackling is heard throughout.
      - Part four, cuid42902D (Box 72, Audiocassette 169_0157)
  - Subseries C: Malcolm X, 1964-1989
    Malcolm X (1925-1965) was an American Civil Rights activist, and a minister and spokesperson for the Nation of Islam.
    - Flyers, Posters, and Ephemera, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "The Crisis of Racism" Panel Discussion, May 1, 1962; cuid42808 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0007)
      This panel discussion featured James Farmer, William Worthy, and Malcolm X; it was broadcasted by WBAI-FM and raised funds for the Monroe defendants.
    - "The Wisdom of Malcolm X: From the Streets of Harlem", August 10, 1963; cuid42809
      Mo' Soul Records
      - Part one, cuid42809A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0009)
      - Part two, cuid42809B (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0010)
    - Speech at the City College of New York by Malcolm X, November 7, 1963; cuid42810
      The two cassette copies are largely duplicates, but both were retained due to inconsistent differences in quality and slight differences in content.
      - Full speech with introduction, cuid42810A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0011)
        Preservation Note: Audio quality is poor.
      - Full speech with additional ending announcement, cuid42810B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0083)
      - Part one, cuid42810C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0084)
        Preservation Note: The volume is very low.
      - Part two, cuid42810D (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0087)
    - "Message to the Grass Roots" by Malcolm X, Northern Negro Grassroots Leadership Conference, November 10, 1963; cuid42859
      Excerpts from an address delivered at King Solomon's Baptist Church, Detroit Michigan, at the Northern Grass Roots Leadership Conference.
      - Mixed Materials (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Audiocassette, cuid42859A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0012)
      - Audio reel, cuid42859B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0080)
        There is content from another speaker in addition to Malcolm X's speech.
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, November, 1963 - April, 1964; cuid42858 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0079)
      Includes both "Message to the Grass Roots" November, 1963 (side 1) and "Malcolm X Speaks Again," March-April, 1964 (side 2)
    - "Malcolm X Speaks Again", circa March-April, 1964; cuid42811 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0013)
    - List of Articles on Malcolm X in The Militant, March 1964 - December 1965 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "The Ballot or the Bullet" by Malcolm X, Cleveland, Ohio, April 3, 1964; cuid42812 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0015)
      Preservation Note: This tape was incubated before its digitization.
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tapes, April 3, 1964; cuid42871
      These tapes include "The Ballot or the Bullet," "The Negro Revolt + What's Next," and Louis Lomax Cleveland Core
      - Parts one and four, cuid42871B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0108)
      - Parts two and three, cuid42871A (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0107)
        Preservation Note: The audio quality is poor and the volume is low.
    - Malcolm X and Louis Lomax, Cleveland, April 3, 1964; cuid42874 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0114)
    - "The Black Revolution" by Malcolm X, Militant Labor Forum, New York City, April 8, 1964; cuid42813
      - Parts one and two, cuid42813A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0017)
        Preservation Note: The audio on side 1 is distorted and loud.
      - Parts one and two, followed by discussion of Freedom Now Party, cuid42873 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0112)
        The discussion following the speech has poor audio quality.
      - Part one, cuid42813B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0095)
        Preservation Note: The audio on track 1 was recorded and transferred at 7.5 ips. Track 2 was recorded at 15 ips and captured at 7.5 ips and then digitally stretched.
        Side two also includes speaker(s) from the Organization of Afro-American Unity Rallies event.
      - Part two, cuid42813C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0096)
        Preservation Note: Track 1 was recorded and transferred at 7.5 ips. From the beginning of track 2 to 00:04:15, the audio was recorded at 15 ips and captured at 7.5 ips and then digitally stretched. On track 2 from 00:09:10 through the end, the audio was recorded and captured at 7.5 ips.
    - "The Ballot or the Bullet" by Malcolm X, Detroit, Michigan, April 12, 1964; cuid42814 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0018)
      Sponsored by Group on Advanced Leadership (GOAL)
      Preservation Note: Inconsistent audio quality and crackling sounds throughout.
    - Malcolm X Compilation Tape, April - July, 1964; cuid42872 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0111)
      This tape includes "Ballot of the Bullet" Rally, King Solomon Baptist Church, Detroit and Malcolm X in Cairo interviewed by Milton Henry.
      Preservation Note: On track 1, the audio from 00:27:43 through the end has poor audio quality.
    - Panel on the Harlem "Hate Gang" Scare, New York City, May, 1964; cuid42822 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0030)
      Featuring Clifton DeBerry of the Socialist Workers Party, Quintin Hand of Harlem Action Group, William Reid of New York CORE, and Malcolm X
    - Militant Labor Forum Panel with Malcolm X, May 29, 1964; cuid42868
      Moderated by Robert Vernon, speakers: Quentin Hand, Clifton DeBerry, William Reed, Malcolm X
      - Speech with Q+A, cuid42868A (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0101)
      - Parts one and four, cuid42868C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0103)
      - Parts two and three, cuid42868B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0102)
        Preservation Note: Side 1 has channel shifting and the audio quality is poor at the beginning; track 1 has low volume.
    - Malcolm X on The Long John Nebel Show, New York City, June 20, 1964; cuid42815
      WOR Radio; Guests: Charles Silberman, P.J. Sydney, Martin Berger, Malcolm X
      - Part one, cuid42815A (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0020)
        Preservation Note: Crackling sounds are heard throughout.
      - Part two, cuid42815B (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0032)
    - Organization of Afro-American Unity Meetings, June - November, 1964; cuid42864 (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0090)
      Track 1 - June 28, 1964 Track 2 - November 29, 1964 Track 3 - August 9, 1964 Track 4 - July 5, 1964
    - Organization of Afro-American Unity Rallies, June - November, 1964; cuid42866
      Includes speeches by Malcolm X, Sharon Jackson, and Lez Edmond
      - Malcolm X speech with Q+A, cuid42866A (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0092)
      - Malcolm X with other speakers, cuid42866B (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0093)
      - Malcolm X speech, Homecoming Rally, cuid42866C (Box 73, Quarter inch audio reel 169_0094)
        Preservation Note: The audio was recorded at 1.875ips and transferred at 3.75 ips, making it digitally stretched.
        Related Materials
        Side 3 content same as 169_0033 ("Organization of Afro-American Unity Homecoming Rally, Audubon Ballroom, New York City"); side 4 content same as 169_0092 ("Organization of Afro-American Unity Rallies -- Malcolm X Speech and Q+A").
    - Malcolm X on The Editors Speak, WLIB New York, July, 1964; cuid42816 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0022)
      Guests: George Schuyler, Allan Morrion; Moderated by George Goodman
    - "Malcolm X: The Cairo Interview", July 17, 1964; cuid42817 (Box 69, Audiocassette 169_0023)